♪〜
〜♪
（風の音）
（ラジオの音声）
タイフーンは現在ニューオレゴンの
東南 …付近を通過中です
The typhoon is currently passing...
... iles away from New Oregon.
暴風は翌朝まで続く見通しで
現在 当局では—
The gale is expected
to last until morning...
... so a strict warning is
still in effect for...
厳重なる警戒を呼びかけて…
（メリル･ストライフ）
これがタイフーン
So this is a typhoon...
I heard the wind can be strong,
but I never dreamed...
風の強いものだと
聞いていましたけど—
こんなに すごいなんて…
She's really huffy, all right!
Definitely a relation of Mr. Vash!
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
さすが ヴァッシュさんの
親戚だけあって—
はちゃめちゃ ビュービューですね
Her name is Jacqueline, and...
名前はジャクリーンさんていう…
おっ？
（２人）うわああ！
（ノックする音）
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
Mr. Vash?
Excuse us...
すいませんが 少しこちらに
お邪魔させて…
...but might we
come in for a...
Huh?
あら？
"Please don't look for me."
- Vash -
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
“捜さないでください
ヴァッシュ”
He got us. Either
he's incredibly slippery...
やられましたわ
さすがに
すばしっこいというか—
...or incredibly crazy to
go out in these conditions!
この状況で出かける神経が
信じられないというか…
It's okay, ma'am!
（ミリィ）大丈夫です 先輩！
I suspected he might do something
like this, so when I had his tray...
私 こんなこともあろうかと
朝ごはんを運ぶふりをして—
中に これを仕込んどいたんです
...I slipped one of these
into his breakfast.
A transmitter!
発信器！
I'm amazed Bernardelli
let you have that!
そんな気の利いたもの
よく会社が渡してくれましたわね
It was a going-away present
from the chief!
はい！ 私 のんきだから—
I goof up so much, he said I should
use any means not to be outwitted!
“出し抜かれないために
手段を選ぶな”って—
部長が せん別に
That is nothing to brag about.
大きい声で言うことじゃなくってよ
（発信器の音）
（ミリィ）ほらほら 近くですよ
Look, look!
He's really close by!
Almost! We'll catch
up to him in no time!
近い！ これなら
すぐ追いかけられます
もうすぐですよ　もうすぐ
We're getting warmer...
Warmer...
（猫の鳴き声）
なんと！ 猫に変身！
Oh, my god!
He turned into a cat!!
Wrong!
違う！
Vash...
（ミリオンズ･ナイヴズ）
ヴァッシュ
Vash!
ヴァッシュ！
Can you stand, Vash?
立てるか？ ヴァッシュ
Here.
ほら
（ヴァッシュ）くっ！
（ナイヴズ）おっと
Oops!
What's wrong? We're
like brothers, aren't we?
何だよ
僕たちは たった２人っきりの
兄弟みたいなものだろ？
This is all your fault!
すべて お前のせいだ！
レムも—
You killed Rem...
The crew...
みんなも—
...you killed them all!!
お前が殺したんだ！
Yes, and it's very colorful.
It's superb...
ああ とても晴れやかだ
すばらしい
...except for the fraction who will
be saved because of Rem's meddling.
レムのせいで助かってしまう—
あの中の数％のこと以外はね
Knives...
（ヴァッシュ）ナイヴズ…
...you...
お前は—
人間じゃない！
...you aren't human!!
（ヴァッシュ）うっ！
（ナイヴズ）当たり前だ！
Damned right I'm not!!
Don't compare me to
those imperfect things!
（ナイヴズ）
あんな不完全なものと
一緒にするな！
（何度も殴る音）
（ナイヴズ）一緒にするな
Don't compare me to them!
Don't compare me to them!!!
（ナイヴズ）一緒にするな！
（ヴァッシュ）うあっ…
You'll see, you trash.
I'll kill you all.
（ナイヴズ）見てろよ ゴミども
すべて消してやる
Only we will be left
on this planet!
この星に我々以外は残さない
レム…
Rem...
Vash...
（レム･セイブレム）ヴァッシュ！
ナイヴズを…
... take care of Knives!
I know, Rem...
分かってるよ レム
I have to face him.
俺は やつと会わなければならない
And then...
そして やつを…
Jacqueline's ankle should pass
near the craggy bluff...
（マックス･サイモン）
ジャクリーンのくるぶしは
13時22分に—
...to the southeast at 1:22 pm.
東南の岩場のすぐ脇を
通過するはずじゃ
I'm counting on you, old man.
信じるぜ ジイさん
間違ってたら化けて出るよ〜
If you're wrong,
I'll haunt you to the grave!!!
おおっ！
ぐわあああ！
んっぐぐぐっ！
It gives me a freaking
heart attack every time!
しかし 何度やっても心臓に悪いよ
See? It's still
going batta-boom...
ほら まだバクバク言ってるし
I thought you were
committing suicide.
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
自殺する気か 思たで
Suicide? I despise
that word the most...
自殺？ それは俺が
一番嫌いな言葉… ん？
What're you doing here?!
なんで君がいるの？ ここに
First you cry your eyes out, and then
you run around jumping off cliffs.
（ウルフウッド）
めそめそ泣いてたか思たら—
今度は好き勝手に動き回りやがって
What are you after?
お前の目的は何なんや？
I'm visiting the folks.
里帰り
Huh? Come again?
あ？ 何やて？
I'M VISITI NG THE FOLKS!!
里帰り！
ハハハハハハッ
空に家でも建っとる言うんか？
Are you saying they built
a house in the sky?
I'm sick of your lies!
お前のウソは聞き飽きたわ！
What is this?
なっ 何や？ これ…
What it looks like.
（ヴァッシュ）見たまんまさ
It's a ship that failed
to crash 130 years ago.
130年前に
地上に落ち損ねたシップだよ
This is unbelievable...
（ウルフウッド）信じられへんな
Who knew the lost technology
was still preserved like this?
ロストテクノロジーが
こないな形で残っとるとは
You said you were
visiting the folks.
お前 里帰り 言うたな？
Are you saying
people live there?
ちゅうことは
あそこに人がおるんか？
I think you'll be their
first houseguest in 20 years.
20年ぶりの
お客さんだと思うよ 君は
M... Mr. Legato...
（レオノフ･ザ･パペットマスター）
レ… レガート様
... he has made his move.
あの男が動きだしました
Also, Vash the Stampede
appears to be working...
（レオノフの声）しかも
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードは—
... with a minister clad in black.
黒服に身を包んだ
牧師と行動しています
I suspect this man is...
もしや あの男は…
Even if he is,
your tasks will not change.
（レガート･ブルーサマーズ）
そうだとしても 君たちが
やるべき行動は変わらないよ
（レオノフ）はっ？
あっ… かしこまりました
Yes. Understood, sir.
You are such a fool...
（レガート）なんて君は愚かなんだ
Had you behaved, you might
have lived to see Doomsday.
動かなければ破滅のときまで
生きていられたというのに
But I'm pleased...
でも 僕はうれしいよ
...for now, I can fulfill
another of my Master's wishes.
だって あの方の願いが
また１つ 成就されるのだから
フフフ フフフフフフッ
（キーボードを打つ音）
Doctor, you won't
believe this!!
（ブラド）先生 大変だぜ！
Someone is here
from the outside?
（先生）おお　外から
人がやってきたんじゃろ
Uh, yeah.
（ブラド）
ええっ？ あ… ああ
It's him. He's back.
彼だよ
彼が帰ってきたんだよ
Is this your first
time meeting him?
お前
会うのは初めてか？
い… いや ６歳のとき１度
No, I met him once
when I was 6.
ハハハハッ
Then this will be your
first time seeing a legend.
ならば伝説を目の当たりにするのは
ほぼ最初だな
Come with me.
ついてきなさい
That man is back?
帰ってきたのか… あの男が
How many years has it been
since I last opened this door?
このドアを開けるのも
何年ぶりかのう
（ブラド）うっ うう…
Is he there?
（ブラド）いるのか？ あそこに
（ヴァッシュ）うぎゃあああ
痛い！ ギブギブ　スーパーギブ！
Ow, mercy, mercy!
Mega-mercy!!
Now that you brought me all this way,
what do you mean I can't come in?!
（ウルフウッド）
こないなとこまで連れてきて—
中に入れられへんちゅうのは
どういうこっちゃ！
Hey, doc!
よう 先生！
ははっ… は
あれがそうなのか？ そうなのか！
Is that him?!
Is THAT him?!
フフッ 変わっとらんの
安心したわい
What a relief!
He hasn't changed a bit.
（ウルフウッド）へええー
You're Brad, aren't you?
You sure have grown.
君がブラドだね　大きくなったな
By the way, who is he?
どころで誰なんだよ？ あいつは
んー それが
よく分かんないんだよね
I'm not quite
sure of that myself.
I don't mind you wandering around
the place, but don't bring outsiders!
（ブラド）あんたが
フラフラするのは勝手だが—
よそもんまで
連れてくるんじゃねえよ！
Oh, don't be like that...
そんな つれないこと言うなて
おっ！
ん？
Don't stare! Inside!
（母親）ダメよ　早く！
That's how it is.
（ブラド）そういうことだ
All right. I'll behave.
分かった　おとなしくしとるわ
Vash!!!
（ジェシカ）ヴァッシュ！
Vash!
ヴァッシュ
Vash!!!
ヴァッシュ！
（ヴァッシュ）
ナハッ ハハハッ！ お嬢さん
ずいぶん いきなりですね
This is all rather
sudden, young lady!
I may be easy, but even I
need a little warning!
さすがの私も心の準備が…
あっ… ああ？
Jessica?
ジェシカ！
That's right!
You remembered!
そうよ  ウフフッ
覚えててくれたんだ
Wow, wow!
This is the coolest!!
チョー感激みたいな感じ！
ウフフッ
（ブラド）この！
（ヴァッシュ）ん？ エヘヘヘヘ
I didn't know you had
such a cute girlfriend!
こんなカワイイ彼女がおったとは
憎いやっちゃな この！
You lucky devil, you!
シー！ シー！
What's this, you
showing off your girl?
何やそれ？ 自慢しとるんか？
I'm sorry, I have
to talk to the doctor.
ごめん！ ちょっと
先生と話があるからさ
Aw, no fair!
えーっ！ そんなあ
Jessica.
ジェシカ！
んんー！
Come see me after, okay?
Right after. Immediately after!
あとで来てよね
きっとね　すぐね！
If you don't, I'll hate you!
来ないと恨む
わ… 分かったから
All right, all right.
I'll just be a second.
ちょっと待っててくれ
（先生）マックスのやつは
元気にしとるかね？
Is Max well?
Yeah, he's doing great! He hasn't
taken an eye off those forecast charts.
（ヴァッシュ）ええ もうピンピン
ずっと予報図とにらめっこですよ
（ウルフウッド）ん？
I haven't introduced myself yet.
自己紹介してへんかったな
わいの名は… あ？
I'm...
当然だ
What did you expect?
The inhabitants here aren't like
you violent, warring outsiders.
ここの住民たちは アウターで
ドンパチやってるやつらとは違う
火薬のにおいを
プンプンさせやがって
You make this place
stink like gunpowder.
あの男が戻ってくるまで
じっとしてろ！ いいな！
Stay put until he gets back!
Got that?
At least offer me a drink,
for crying out loud!
（ウルフウッド）
茶ぐらい出さんかい！ まったく
For crying out loud!
We barely manage to find him...
（メリル）まったく
会ったばかりだってのに—
...and already he slips out
from under our noses!
早速 出し抜いてくれましたわね
あの人は
（ミリィ）
先輩 ダメですって 危険ですよ！
Ma'am, listen! We can't go
out there! It's too dangerous!
仕事を放棄するわけには
いかなくってよ
We can't abandon our duties!
（２人）うわあああーっ！
A city cradled
in lost technology.
（ウルフウッド）
ロストテクノロジーに囲まれた町か
I'm starting to see what
makes you tick, Needle-noggin.
少しずつ読めてきたで トンガリ
（子ども）こっから出てけ！
Get out of here!!
あっ ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
Don't sweat it.
ええて
（母親）でも
私もこの子と気持ちは同じです
But I feel the same as the boy.
I beg you, please
leave this place.
お願いですから 早く
ここから立ち去ってください
Why, so you can all live out
your cozy little lives?
そんで自分らは ぬくぬくと
暮らしますっちゅうわけや
（母親）え？
Your plants aren't inexhaustible.
They could break down someday.
ここにあるプラントかて
無限やない
いつ壊れるかもしれへんのんや
You can't cling
to them forever.
何かにすがったまま
生き続けられるわけちゃうで
（市民Ａ）何を言ってる！
What are you talking about?!
You have no idea...
このシステムを維持するために—
...how hard we work
to maintain these systems!
我々が どれだけ苦労しているか
知りもしないくせに！
l-It's better than
living out there!
（市民Ｂ）
アウターに降りるよりマシだ！
They say you care nothing
about people's lives!
（市民Ｃ）
あんたらは人の命を—
何とも思っていない
そうじゃないか！
Hear, hear!
（市民Ｄ）そうだ そうだ！
（市民たち）あっ ああ…
Like it or not,
the time will come!!
イヤでも何でも 必ず来るんや！
The time will come for all of you
to live on that desert planet!
あんたらが
あの砂漠だらけの星の上で—
生活していかなあかんときがな！
Anything new happen
while I was away?
（ヴァッシュ）
何か変わったことはありましたか？
Not really. They're still
sleeping in suspended animation.
（先生）相変わらずだ
時間を止めて 眠り続けとる
Oh.
そっかあ
（先生）みんな心配しとったんじゃ
We were all worried sick. You've
been out of touch for nearly 5 years.
５年近く
連絡がつかなかったからの
I'm sorry.
すいません
5 years is probably the blink
of an eye to you, anyway.
まっ！ あんたにとっちゃ—
５年なんて
一瞬のことかもしれねえがな
That's enough, Brad!
He isn't that sort of a person!
（先生）やめんか ブラド！
彼は そんな人間じゃない
Person?
人間？ フッ！
A person, huh?
人間ね
But since you've returned,
I suppose it isn't over yet.
（先生）
だが ここに来たということは
まだ決着がついとらんようだな
Did you come into contact with him
in the 5th moon incident?
フィフスムーン事件のとき
やつと接触したのか？
Not directly, but I think
he had a hand in it.
直接じゃないけど
関与はしていると思う
My memory of it is gone,
just like the time with July.
僕の記憶がジュライのときと
同じように ぶっ切れてるしね
Did you fire it?
（先生）あれを撃ったのか？
Hey! Just a
damned minute!!
おい！ おいおい
Doesn't that make you the
more destructive of the two?!
じゃあ ホントに疫病神なのは
お前のほうじゃねえのか！
Enough, Brad!
（先生）やめろ！ ブラド
- Well, doesn't it?!
- Brad...
どうなんだよ！
（先生）ブラド！
ああ そうかもしれない
Yes. It might.
冗談じゃねえ　冗談じゃねえぞ！
That's not funny.
That's not funny!!
Who came up with
such a risky idea?!
誰が そんなリスキーな話を！
そんなことは分かっとる
I know that!
However, the only one who
has opposed him and lived...
だが 今まであの男と敵対して
消されずに生還できたのは—
この優男(やさおとこ)だけなのじゃよ
...is that gentle man.
（ブラド）んん！
Will you believe me?
僕を信じてくれないか？
頼む
Please.
（ブラド）チッ！
（ドアの開閉音）
I'm sorry.
（先生）すまん
No, he's right.
いや
そりゃそうだよ
To ordinary people,
I must seem like a monster.
普通の人間から見れば
僕は化け物だ
んまっ！ それも半分じゃ
Well, that's only half of it.
He's in love with Jessica.
あいつ ジェシカに
ホレよってな
Apparently, he told
her so a short time ago.
このあいだ 告白したらしい
Jessica...
ジェシカ！
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさーい　私…
（ブラド）かっ…
...I'm going to marry Vash!
（ジェシカ）
ヴァッシュのお嫁さんになるの
なるのー なるのー！
No!
...I'm going to marry Vash!
... marry Vash! ...marry Vash!
それが残りの半分じゃ
エヘヘヘヘッ
That's the other half.
What's this?
これは！
You wanted this, didn't you?
こいつが欲しかったんじゃろ？
（ジェシカの鼻歌）
（ジェシカ）フフフフッ
（ジェシカ）
せっかく戻ってきたってのに
ヴァッシュったら
He's back, but he
isn't being much fun.
At least he hasn't changed!
He hasn't changed a bit!
でも変わってなかった
全然 変わってなかった！
ヴァッシュー！
Vash!
Wait! Wait for me!
待ってよー 待って！
あああー
なーんてね なんてね　エヘッ
うぶだね 私も  アハハハッ！
Look at me!
I'm so naive!
ウハハハハハッ
Of all the rotten,
ignorant people!
どいつもこいつも
根性 腐りおってからに！
Doesn't anybody take
the word of a priest anymore?!
牧師の言うことが
聞けんちゅうのか！
（市民の叫び声）
What's wrong?
Hey, in there!
どないした？ おい コラ！
（銃声と市民の悲鳴）
Don't make doors
that can't be opened!!
（ウルフウッド）
わけ分からんドア 作るな！
（市民Ａ）ああっ！
あっ ああ… あんた！
Y-You...
What are you doing?!
（市民Ｂ）な… 何してんだよ！
It wasn't me. They were
like this when I got here.
（ウルフウッド）わいとちゃうで
来たときには
こんな状況になっとったんや
Hey, listen to me!
おい！ 話 聞けや！
（ブラド）何があった！
What happened?!
- Brad!
- It's Terry and Nasha!
ブ… ブラド！
テリーとナシュアが…
（ブラド）あっ！ あ… ああ
貴様！ 貴様！
You! You!!
It wasn't me.
わいやあらへん
Will you believe me?
僕を信じてくれないか
You can't prove that!
根拠が ねえだろうが！
This is great.
It's the smoothest one yet!
いいねえ
今までよりスムーズだよ
Come on, we'd better hurry.
It's gotten really late.
さっ！ 急がないと
かなり遅くなってしまった
Jessica will be furious.
ジェシカのやつ むくれとるぞ
はて？ どこに行ったのやら
That's funny...
Where is she?
Oh, yes. She wanted
to give you that.
おおー それ
あの子のプレゼントだ
She was really looking
forward to your return.
お前が帰ってくるのを楽しみに
ずーっと待っておった
- Doctor...
- Hm?
（ヴァッシュ）先生…
（先生）ん？
（先生）はっ！ なに！
What...
Once again,
it wasn't me.
もういっぺん言うで
わいやあらへん
Shut up, you
murdering outsider!
黙れ！ 人殺しのアウター野郎が！
You're serious, aren't you?
（ウルフウッド）マジやな？
You seriously want to
fight me, don't you?
マジで わいと
やるっちゅうんやな？
Hey, what are you doing?!
おい 何をする！
Joseph!
（ブラド）ジョセフ！
（ウルフウッド）あっ！
Move it!!
どかんかい！
あっ！
You did this!
てめえの仕業か！
Back, you fool!
顔出すな アホ！
You're no match
for the likes of him!
お前ごときが相手になるような
やつやないで！
（ブラド）ああ…
Leonof, I presume?
レオノフやな？
Oh? I'm honored
you know my name!
（レオノフの声）ほう  私の名前を
存じてもらえているとは光栄だね
We've never met,
but I've heard of you...
あなたとは初めて会うが
そのうわさは聞いているよ
... the man who rings
the black funeral bell...
弔いの黒き鐘を鳴らす男
... Chapel the...
その名はチャペル…
Don't say it,
you doll fetishist!
（ウルフウッド）
言うな！ 人形風情が！
Holy shit!
（ブラド）すげえ！
This is just a warm-up
for both of us.
（ウルフウッド）小手調べや
こっちも 向こうもな
That's right.
（レオノフの声）そのとおりだ
It wouldn't be difficult
to beat you now...
このまま
君を倒すのは容易だが—
... but that would be boring.
それでは刺激が足りなくていけない
How about this?
こういうのは いかがかな？
Jessica!!
ジェシカ！
I've been watching you
through his eyes the entire time.
（レオノフの声）
この子の目を通して
ずーっと見ていたよ
I know you have feelings
for this young lady.
君が この女性に
好意を抱いていることもね
You know what I'm
getting at, don't you?
何を言いたいか 分かるだろう？
（銃のトリガーを引く音）
You peace-dulled fool!
Can't you see it's a trap?!
平和ぼけのドアホが！
ワナっちゅうことも分からんのか
I know it's a trap.
分かってるよ
Then lower your piece!
（ウルフウッド）
ほなら 獲物 下ろせや
But there's...
ほかに…
...there's no
other way!!
ほかに
どうしようもねえじゃねえか！
There is another way.
（ウルフウッド）方法はあるで
If we ignore the girl's plight,
we will definitely make it through.
あのお嬢ちゃんを見捨てたら
少なくとも２人は助かる
What did you say?!
なんだと！
I think that is
the best option.
わいは それが最善やと思う
It's the only way any
of us will survive this.
２人だけでも
確実に生き残る方法や
Shut up!!
言うな！
However, I know a guy
who whines and cries...
けどな 困ったときに
そんなんはイヤや言うて—
...until he finds a way
to save everyone.
泣きながら全員を助けようとする
やつがおるねん
A man who takes a stand...
体じゅう傷だらけにしながら
それでも立ち上がる男がな
...though it scars him
from head to toe.
And he's right there!
そこにな！
（銃声）
（ブラド）あっ！
（発砲音）
（ジェシカのおびえる声）
Jessica!
（ブラド）ジェシカ！
大丈夫か？ ケガは…
ケガはないか！
Are you all right?!
Did they hurt you?!
N-No...
You took too long.
待たせすぎやで
（ヴァッシュ）花… 赤い花
A flower...
A red flower.
Isn't it pretty?
It's called a geranium.
（レム）キレイでしょ？
ゼラニウムっていうのよ
There are more types
of flowers on Earth.
地球では もっと
たくさんの種類の花が咲いていてね
They are very dear
to people's hearts.
人にとって とても身近なものなの
食べられるの？
Can you eat them?
ウフッ そういうのもあるけどね
Well, some flowers
can be eaten...
Do you like flowers, Rem?
（ヴァッシュ）レムは花が好き？
I love flowers. Red flowers
are often used to describe love.
大好きよ
赤い花は
よく愛情に例えられるわ
Even the tiniest flowers that
brave the elements are wonderful.
大輪じゃなくても
自然に強く咲く花はステキよ
でもね
But in flower language,
red geraniums have another meaning.
ゼラニウムの赤い花には
別の意味もあるの
They mean "determination."
花言葉は〝決意〞
Hey! Where did you
get that red coat?!
お前！ その赤いコート
Vash the Stampede!
ヴァッシュ･ザ…
スタンピード！
（ジェシカ）あーん
Vash, Vash, Vash!
ヴァッシュ ヴァッシュ
ヴァッシュ！
I was so scared!
私 怖かったよー
Hey, hey!
（ヴァッシュ）
ちょっと ちょっと
Are we upset?
お怒りですかあ？
（レオノフの声）
フッフッフッフッフッ
You act as though
this has ended.
まるで大団円だ
Some of my children
are still there.
まだ私の子どもたちは
残っているというのに
それにガンホーガンズが
一人でやってくると—
And besides,
who ever said...
... the Gung-Ho Guns
call one at a time?
誰が言ったかな？
なんだと！
What?!
（ヴァッシュ）３人？
Three of them!
（レオノフ）
そうだ　３人の魔神が
ここに来ているのだよ
That's right.
Three demons...
...have arrived.
This is your big
comeback celebration...
（レオノフの声）君の復帰祝いだよ
... Vash the Stampede.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
（メリルとミリィ）ぎゃあああー！
イヤアアアー！
♪〜
〜♪
Some things you can't give up.
Some things you want to protect.
（ヴァッシュ）譲れないものがある
守りたいものがある
Sometimes we must take a stand
no matter what kind of pain awaits.
どんな苦しみが
待っているとしても—
立ち上がらなければならない
ときがある
The man in the red coat
took up his gun once again...
赤いコートをまとった男は
再び銃を手にした
...in order to stop the grief.
これ以上
悲しみを増やさないために
...in order to stop the hatred.
これ以上
憎しみを増やさないために
I keep the word of the red geranium,
which taught to me so long ago...
はるかな昔—
ゼラニウムの花を前にして
教えられた花言葉を—
...I keep firm determination
deep in my heart.
揺るぎない決意を胸に秘めて